KSHITIJ PATHANIA

Member of Technical Staff

- @ kshitijpathania@gmail.com
- in Kshitij Pathania

J 09354164254

Roorkee, India



SKILLS

C++ Java ML

Nodejs Reactjs DevOps

SpringBoot Docker

Kubernetes

INTERESTS

AI NLP CV

System Design

LANGUAGES

Lang 1: Hindi

Lang 2: English

AWARDS

Jee Advanced Rank: 3519

Summer Undergraduate Research Award: 2017

Inspire Scholarship Holder: 2015-2020

REFERENCES

Ref 1

in R. Balasubramanian Professor bala@cs.iitr.ac.in IIT ROORKEE 09068680077

Ref 2

in Dr. Sanjeev Malik Associate Professor malikfma@iitr.ac.in IIT ROORKEE 01332-285824

ABOUT ME

Experienced Software Development Engineer with skills in Algorithms Implementation, Web development, Application development, Machine learning, and Deep learning. Strong engineering professional with a degree in Integrated MS in Applied Mathematics from Indian Institute of Technology, Roorkee.

EXPERIENCE

Member of Technical Staff-2 | Adobe

iii 01 2022 - Current

Noida, India

- Designed and developed a content management system to cater linguistic and functional testing activities in Adobe
- Implemented deployment pipelines to ensure services are reliably deployed on K8 clusters

Member of Technical Staff | Adobe

= 07 2020 - 12 2021

Noida, India

- Developed a web application used by Adobe Localization Team for workflow orchestration of localisation tasks.
- Contributed in the development of various APIs and microservices for leveraging products testing in Adobe
- Implemented and integrated an NLP transformer-based solution to solve line break issue in the thai language

Research Intern | Adobe

= 05 2019 - 07 2019

Bangalore, India

- Built a data-driven attribution model for B2B market transactions.
- Explored literature based on various types of LSTMs, survival theory and deep-learning for designing the architecture of the attribution model.

Google Summer of Code 2018 | Libreoffice

= 05 2018 - 08 2018

Global Event

- Selected for Google Summer of Code 2018 in the organization LibreOffice as a student developer.
- The work focused on making the notebook bar UI bugs free and solving the issues related to resizing, theming, and other issues with widgets.

EDUCATION

Computer Science | Georgia Institute of Technology

1 01 2023 - Current

Atlanta, US

• Ongoing Masters in Computer Science

Applied Mathematics | Indian Institute of Technology Roorkee

= 07 2015 - 05 2020

Roorkee, India

• Integrated Masters in Applied Mathematics, CGPA: 8.23

- Associate Coordinator, Training and Placement Office (IIT Roorkee)
- Coordinator, Ravindra Bhawan Sports Meet
- Member, National Sports Organisation (NSO)

PROJECTS

Word spotting in Handwritten Documents | Project

= 05 2017 - 08 2017

- IIT Roorkee, India
- This Project was done under the valuable guidance of Prof. Partha Pratim Roy.
- Implemented Phoc(Pyramidal histogram of characters) in a region-based convolution network for segmentation free word spotting
- Achieved map of 91.6 in query be example word spotting

Market Analysis of Bitcoins in India | Project

i 08 2017 - 11 2017

- IIT Roorkee, India
- This project was done under the valuable guidance of Prof. J.K Nayak
- Analysed and interpreted the sampled data using IBM SPSS Statistics and Percentage analysis.
- Concluded multiple hypothesis related to bitcoins in India using ANOVA, Chi-Square and other methodologies needed for hypothesis testing.

Machine Translation and Zero-shot Sentiment Analysis in Sanskrit | Dissertation

1 01 2020 - 05 2020

- IIT Roorkee, India
- Implemented various seq2seq architectures to achieve translation from Sanskrit to English
- A GAN-based strategy is designed to evaluate the quality of translations
- Used various state-of-the-art sentimental analysis models like bert to obtain sentiment scores of Sanskrit text
- Achieved accuracy of 80.67 by using attention-based LSTM

PUBLICATIONS

Zero-shot learning based cross-lingual sentiment analysis for Sanskrit text with insufficient labeled data | Journal

2022

- Applied Intelligence (APIN)
- Novel methodology for analyzing the sentiments portrayed by Sanskrit text has been proposed
- This research was supported by Ministry of Human Resource Development (MHRD)
- A dataset of Sanskrit and English translation along with their marked sentiment scores has been constructed
- The paper got accepted in Springer Applied Intelligence (APIN) Journal: https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10489-022-04046-6